To an outsider, any culture can seem quirky, confusing, peculiar or just downright bizarre.
在外人看来，任何文化都可能显得古怪、令人费解、奇怪，或者干脆就是完全莫名其妙。
And the UK's got a thing or two that raises a few eyebrows.
而英国就有那么一两件事会让人瞠目结舌。
Brits are quite capable of befuddling visitors with their idiosyncrasies.
英国人完全能用他们独特的癖好把游客们搞糊涂。
However, understand the why and things might be less perplexing.
然而，一旦理解了其中的缘由，事情可能就没那么令人困惑了。
Here are the reasons for three of Britain's more puzzling practices.
以下就是英国三个令人费解的习惯的成因。
In a world where 61% of nations drive on the right, the unorthodox Brits drive on the left.
在这个世界上61%的国家都靠右行驶，而不守常规的英国人却靠左行驶。
Why?
为什么呢？
"Most people think it goes back to Medieval, maybe even Roman times," explains Stephen Laing, curator of the British Motor Museum.
“大多数人认为这可以追溯到中世纪，甚至可能是罗马时代，”英国汽车博物馆馆长斯蒂芬·莱恩解释道。
This unusual behaviour makes sense when you remember that right-handed people wear a sword on their left hip.
当你记得右撇子会把剑佩在左胯时，这种不寻常的行为就说得通了。
Travelling on the left allowed you to keep your weapon arm toward your opponent, who would be on your right.
靠左行驶可以让你的持剑手臂（右手）朝向在你的右侧的对手。
This practice persisted until the 18th Century when a law was passed requiring all traffic crossing London Bridge to keep to the left.
这种做法一直持续到18世纪，当时通过了一项法律，要求所有通过伦敦桥的车辆都必须靠左行驶。
Visitors to the UK that have just washed their hands in an old-fashioned sink might be wondering why one tap is solely for hot water, the other exclusively cold.
在英国，用老式洗手池洗过手的游客可能会纳闷，为什么一个水龙头只出热水，另一个只出冷水。
Either can make washing very uncomfortable.
用哪一种洗手都会让人很不舒服。
So, why this oddity?
那么，为什么会有这种怪事呢？
"It relates to a time when hot and cold water were kept separate to prevent contamination," Kevin Wellman, chief executive officer of the Chartered Institute of Plumbing and Heating Engineering says.
“这关系到过去一个为了防止污染而将冷热水分开的时代，”特许管道与供暖工程学会的首席执行官凯文·威尔曼说。
Drinkable cold water came from a mains supply, but hot water came from attic tanks and was not considered suitable for consumption.
可饮用的冷水来自市政供水系统，而热水则来自阁楼的水箱，被认为不适合饮用。
So they were kept apart.
所以它们被分开了。
Millions of people drink tea worldwide, but the eccentric Brits put milk in theirs.
全球有数百万人喝茶，但古怪的英国人却会在茶里加牛奶。
Why?
为什么呢？
This mystifying practice relates to the quality of china cup used in the 18th Century when tea was first imported.
这种令人困惑的做法与18世纪茶叶刚进口时使用的瓷杯质量有关。
For the majority of Brits, "the cups available couldn’t withstand the heat of the boiling water and would shatter, so milk was added first," Simon Hill, Tea Buyer at Bettys & Taylors of Harrogate tells the Sun newspaper.
对大多数英国人来说，“当时能买到的杯子承受不住沸水的热度会破裂，所以要先加牛奶，”哈罗盖特Bettys & Taylors公司的茶叶采购员西蒙·希尔告诉《太阳报》。
This cooled the cup enough to withstand the water.
这样可以冷却杯子，使其足以承受热水。
And this practical tweak soon became a national habit.
而这个实用的小微调很快就成了全国性的习惯。
There's a method to the madness, they say.
人们说，疯狂之中亦有章法。
As you can see, these quirky Brits have perfectly coherent reasons for left-hand driving, two-tap sinks and tea with milk.
正如你所见，这些古怪的英国人对于左驾行驶、双龙头水槽和奶茶有着非常合理的理由。
But until you comprehend them, they can seem unfathomable.
但在你理解它们之前，它们似乎深奥莫测。
Even if they still seem strange, at least now you're in the know.
即使它们现在看来仍然很奇怪，但至少你现在知道其中的缘由了。